{
    "title": "SQLite",
    "sources": [
        "https://cheatography.com/richardjh/cheat-sheets/sqlite3/"
    ],
    "cards": [
        {
            "question": ".backup ?DB? FILE",
            "answer": "Backup DB (default \"\u00admai\u00adn\") to FILE",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".bail ON|OFF",
            "answer": "Stop after hitting an error. Default OFF",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".databases",
            "answer": "List names and files of attached databases",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".dump ?TABLE? ...",
            "answer": "Dump the database in an SQL text format.",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".echo ON|OFF",
            "answer": "Turn command echo on or off",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".exit",
            "answer": "Exit this program",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".explain ?ON|OFF?",
            "answer": "Turn output mode suitable for EXPLAIN on or off.",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".header(s) ON|OFF",
            "answer": "Turn display of headers on or off",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".help",
            "answer": "Shows this inform\u00adation.",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".import FILE TABLE",
            "answer": "Import data from FILE into TABLE",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".indices ?TABLE?",
            "answer": "Show names of all indices",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".load FILE ?ENTRY?",
            "answer": "Load an extension library",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".log FILE|off",
            "answer": "Turn logging on or off. FILE can be stderr\u00ad/stdout",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".mode MODE ?TABLE?",
            "answer": "Set output mode where MODE is one of: csv, column, html, insert, line, list, tabs, tcl",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".nullvalue STRING",
            "answer": "Print STRING in place of NULL values",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".output FILENAME",
            "answer": "Send output to FILENAME",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".output stdout",
            "answer": "Send output to the screen",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".prompt MAIN CONTINUE",
            "answer": "Replace the standard prompts",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".quit",
            "answer": "Exit this program",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".read FILENAME",
            "answer": "Execute SQL in FILENAME",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".restore ?DB? FILE",
            "answer": "Restore content of DB (default \"\u00admai\u00adn\") from FILE",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".schema ?TABLE?",
            "answer": "Show the CREATE statements",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".separator STRING",
            "answer": "Change separator used by output mode and .import",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".show",
            "answer": "Show the current values for various settings",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".stats ON|OFF",
            "answer": "Turn stats on or off",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".tables ?TABLE?",
            "answer": "List names of tables",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".timeout MS",
            "answer": "Try opening locked tables for MS millis\u00adeconds",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".width NUM1 NUM2 ...",
            "answer": "Set column widths for \"\u00adcol\u00adumn\u00ad\" mode",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": ".timer ON|OFF",
            "answer": "Turn the CPU timer measur\u00adement on or off",
            "category": "Meta Commands",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-init file",
            "answer": "Read and execute commands from file , which can contain a mix of SQL statements and meta-c\u00adomm\u00adands.",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-echo",
            "answer": "Print commands before execution.",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-[no]h\u00adeader",
            "answer": "Turn headers on or off.",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-bail",
            "answer": "Stop after hitting an error.",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-inter\u00adactive",
            "answer": "Force intera\u00adctive I/O .",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-batch",
            "answer": "Force batch I/O .",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-column",
            "answer": "Query results will be displayed in a table like form, using whitespace characters to separate the columns and align the output.",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-csv",
            "answer": "Set output mode to CSV (comma separated values).",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-html",
            "answer": "Query results will be output as simple HTML tables.",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-line",
            "answer": "Query results will be displayed with one value per line, rows separated by a blank line. Designed to be easily parsed by scripts or other programs",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-list",
            "answer": "Query results will be displayed with the separator (|, by default) character between each field value. The default.",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-separator separator",
            "answer": "Set output field separator. Default is \"|\".",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-stats",
            "answer": "Print memory stats before each finalize.",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-nullvalue string",
            "answer": "Set string used to represent NULL values. Default is (empty string).",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-version",
            "answer": "Show SQLite version.",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-vfs name",
            "answer": "Use name as the default VFS .",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "-help",
            "answer": "Show help on options and exit.",
            "category": "Options",
            "notes": ""
        }
    ]
}